Amit Bhalla



bhallaamit2004@yahoo.com



973-33877053



linkedin.com/in/amit-bhalla-1353877

Summary

Telecom & Fintech Professional, IIM Calcutta Alumni, 21 years of experience in Sales, Business Development & Profit & loss accountability, with specialization in B2B merchant acquisition in Telecom, wallet, Payments, Remittance & SME Lending Business.

Accomplished Professional within Sales, Distribution, Retail, Key Account, Strategic Planning, Marketing, CRM.

Leading the creation and execution of sales plans to optimize revenue, product and service exposure, penetrate targeted markets, and capture strong and sustainable growth. Skilled at building strong relationships with an external business partner, vendors, suppliers, and staff at all levels; dedicated to surpassing goals.

Experienced in formulating strategies for Businesses - SME Lending, Money Remittance. POS, Mini ATM, eWallet, eVoucher, Mobile Banking & Telecom Prepaid & Postpaid Business

- Sales Channel Development and Distribution
- Retail Management and Key Account Management
- Strategic Alliances
- Product Life Cycle Management
- Business Development & Revenue Growth
- Business Process Engineering
- · Leadership, Training, Coaching & Mentoring
- · Budgets, P&L,

Experience

as Center Head

Arab Financial Services

Dec 2019 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

- Arranging responsible funding for SMEs in UK & US markets
- · Lead the establishment and attainment of appropriate revenue targets for each core vertical
- Provide regular coaching and guidance to the Sales Team
- Be an advocate within the organization to help the team succeed
- Play a key role in setting long term revenue growth objectives
- · Directly responsible for the company's new sales revenue in the global Financial Services industry
- Develop plans and strategies for developing business and achieving the sales goals
- Strategically develop and Cross & Upsell existing accounts in close cooperation with the Engagement Team
- · Lead all sales efforts towards successful growth
- Manage key prospects and customer relationships including leading and participating in closing strategic opportunities
- · Provide detailed and accurate sales forecasting
- Create infrastructure and systems to support the success of the sales function
- Compile information and data related to customer and prospect interactions

 Monitor customer, market activity and provide feedback to company leadership team and other company functions

National Sales Head

MoneyOnMobile India

Dec 2015 - Oct 2019 (3 years 11 months)

Products - Wallet business- Money Remittance, POS, Mini ATM, Travel, Mobile Top-ups, Lending

Setting up Distribution Network Pan India B2B Merchant acquisition

SMEs/ Govt organisations

Processing Volume 2 Billion USD per annum

10000 SMEs /30,000 Transacting distributors, 120,000 Transacting Retailers

Churn management

Channel ROI model

Retail Penetration

Market segmentation

- Execute business strategy
- Align the team internally on a go-to-market strategy for the payments product offering, work closely with Sales, Marketing, Technology, and Product
- Lead the launch of new products, set revenue targets for new channels, build multi-year strategic plans
- Manage all KPI's, metrics (incl conversion and churn) for payments business, put in place benchmarks for payments processing products, lead the way to achieve those marks
- Responsible for the relationship management of channel partners
- The building, maintaining, and managing relationships with current and prospective channel partners.
- Selling through to end users through channel partner sales resources.
- · Meeting targets for sales volume.

v ZBM

Videocon Telecommunications Ltd

Aug 2009 - Dec 2015 (6 years 5 months)

Videocon Telecommunications Ltd 6 years 5 months Key Highlights:

- Utilizing experience-backed judgment, strong work ethics, and irreproachable integrity for orchestrating revenue growth and sales targets, steering and promoting ARPU development
- Overcoming complex business challenges through all channels of sales to increase the reach and availability
- Managing a team of 100 sales employees and 550 indirect employees through a channel partner
- Characterizing as a visionary, strategist & tactician for steering product distribution, supply chain, service center.
- Generating sales through Retail (80 Retail Stores), Indirect Sales (Distribution), SME, Outbound (Tele calling having 30% sales contribution), and Govt. Segment
- Catering to 40,000 + Distribution Outlets, 14,000 SME Accounts, and 30 Govt. Segment Accounts for sales
- Delivering mission-critical results; motivating teams and establishing innovative marketing strategies along with enhancing the product and brand image in the market

Highlights:

- Harvested untapped business opportunities, contributed to the generation of 35% of the company's revenue
- Effectuated and promoted growth of VIDEOCON Telecom in Haryana; acquired 25% market share in a span of 3 years
- Envisioned and created successful outcomes; steered the launch of Mobile Financial Service Wallet Service in the country

oxigen. Zonal Head

Oxigen

Jan 2008 - Aug 2009 (1 year 8 months)

Zonal head - Upper North India

Oxigen Services 1 year 8 months

- · Online recharge market penetration
- · Monitored the market share for acquisition and revenue purpose
- · Formulated sales targets of acquisition and revenue for the team members
- · Looked after the complete sales operations for business growth & excellence
- · Identified channel partners and maintained healthy relationships with them
- · Executed various sales training manual for the sales team as well as guided them about technical exercise
- · Performed marketing and customer relationship management activities for streamlined operations

Highlights:

· Successfully improved the:

Distributor strength to 150 Distributors wit in 12 Months Revenue USD 2 Million / month in 12 months 10 K Retailer base in 12 months

· Holds the merit of receiving Best Circle Award in May'08

RELIANCE Cluster Prepaid lead

Reliance Communications

2004 - 2009 (6 years)

- Spearheaded Zonal sales and distribution of Voice, Data, Landline, PCO products
- Steered direct and indirect sales channel through Direct Sales Team of 55 people and Indirect Sales Team of 500 people through channel partners
- Catered to Enterprise, SME, Retailers & Distributors
- · Effectuated product promotion and launch, market expansion, and augmented market share
- Led yearly revenue of INR 4 Million through prepaid recharge sales
- · Recognised with an award for Best cluster head -Sales in 2006
- Spearheaded 17000+ point of retail sales
- Orchestrated sales network through 600 corporate clients, 5,000 SME, 15,000 retailers across the Zone
- Monitored and supervised operations of Mobile Top Up

Education



Indian Institute of Management, Calcutta

Executive Senior Management Program

2013 - 2015

Bangalore University

Bachelor of Hotel Management, Bachelor of Hotel Management. 1996 - 1999 M.S.Ramaiah College, Bangalore

Skills

Sales • Sales Management • Sales Process • Direct Sales • Customer Service • New Business Development • Team Management • Channel Partners • CRM • Telecommunications